<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-10-01T07:50:43-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">henry y.</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">unsighted (full review) (in progress)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/unsighted.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="unsighted (full review) (in progress)" /><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/unsighted</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/unsighted.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/unsighted.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;unsighted&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: studio pixel punk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes (local)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 30, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, switch, playstation, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: /10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: n/a hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Progress&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">death’s gambit: afterlife (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/deathsgambit.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="death's gambit: afterlife (full review)" /><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/deathsgambit</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/deathsgambit.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/deathsgambit.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;death’s gambit: afterlife&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: white rabbit&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: metroidvania action platformer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 30, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, switch, playstation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 13 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death’s Gambit: Afterlife Review: Relics of Undying Passion&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s a rare sight to see developers push anything more than a few small patches to their already released games, let alone an entire revamp version with additional content and free of charge. However, developer White Rabbit demonstrates their passion and dedication to their 2018 release of Death’s Gambit.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, Death’s Gambit: Afterlife is the reimagining of the original game, boasting a complete mechanical overhaul, alternate endings, new bosses and areas to explore, more weapons, and a slew of quality-of-life changes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For those unfamiliar, Death’s Gambit is a Souls-like Metroidvania that follows Sorun, a soldier granted immortality and employed under Death himself to rid the land of Siradon of its curse. The game pays homage in more than obvious ways to Dark Souls, as you must first pick a class before beginning a new game. Further, areas can be found called Aldwynn, Central Sanctuary, and Caer Siorai, which sound a lot like the namings of Gwyn, Firelink Shrine, and Anor Londo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;These are merely inspirations, though, as gameplay puts a twist on the dark medieval fantasy action RPG genre. As you progress, you inherit the skill tree of a different class, allowing for hybrid build playstyles. Additionally, when you fall to a boss, you are immediately rewarded with souls based on how much health remains on the boss, allowing you to potentially level up before you try again. Thankfully, you don’t lose all your souls after dying. Instead, you drop a healing plume (this game’s Estus Flask).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The narrative in Death’s Gambit is vague, with snippets of lore that are loosely woven together by your own interpretation. The game digs into Sorun’s backstory and his ever-longing search for his mother in the lost realm of Siradon. Many themes of life, death, and immortality are touched upon as you piece together the story through talking to various characters and flashbacks to when Sorun was a child. There’s also a bit of humor as Death himself has a comical personality.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death’s Gambit: Afterlife is visually stunning with its beautifully drawn pixel art. The dark medieval tone is accentuated by the pixelated design that makes the visual experience a spectacle. From the depressing feel of Darkness Falls to the foresty vibe of Warden’s Sanctum, each new area allowed for a refreshing take on scenery. To my surprise, there’s actually voice acting in Death’s Gambit, which is a rare sight in an indie game. However, for some reason, Sorun, the main character is unvoiced, while all other major characters are voiced. To further set the mood is an evoking orchestral score, fitting the setting wherever you go.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death’s Gambit: Afterlife has perfected its combat system across various updates found in this release. Of course, your attacks and dodges consume stamina, but you also have the ability to execute a perfect block and parry, allowing you to counter the enemy and heal some health back.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before you begin the game, you can test each class and their respective weapons and abilities before committing to one. In addition, changes to input buffering have been made, with attacks being able to change directions after the animation has already started. Further, an interesting take on combat is the introduction of the soul meter, which fills as you land hits and is used to execute weapon arts or defensive spells.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat has received some rebalancing, most noticeable in the talent tree and Metroidvania abilities. Former abilities that had to be purchased with points via the talent tree are now automatically unlocked after defeating certain bosses. In addition, classes such as the Blood Knight have been nerfed. Instead of regaining health if you quickly retaliate, you now have to land an ability instead. Furthermore, the healing animation executes faster but heals for less. These small quality-of-life changes make a big impact on how the overall gameplay mechanics and progression feel.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Afterlife adds an additional six bosses to the already beefy fourteen that exist. Every themed area is capped off with a boss encounter for you to take on. While many games attempt to demonstrate the pinnacle excellence of Souls-like bosses, very few do them correctly. This is not the case with Death’s Gambit: Afterlife. Most bosses in Afterlife are daunting, but there’s always a fair balance that makes them really fun to fight and challenging to take on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The boss design weaves in environmental platforming in addition to the head-on combat with each one you face. The entire platform is tilting, so you need to balance by making your way to the other side. The floor is engulfed in flames, so you need to grab the Metroidvania fly crystal to fly around the arena. There is a sniper aimed at you, so you need to hide behind a pillar to block the shot. This is an excellent demonstration of the culmination of different genres Afterlife set out to be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death’s Gambit: Afterlife boasts an incredible amount of replay-ability. Not only does the game offer incentive to replay with its seven unique classes with a total of over 100 talents and new game plus features, it also features infinitely replay-able heroic boss encounters. These “heroic” versions of bosses not only make them deal more damage and contain more health but also display entirely new moves and abilities, making each fight significantly more challenging and exciting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The original game back in 2018 was heavily criticized for its technical shortcomings, ranging from stutters and frame drops to corrupted save files and crashes. While Afterlife improves on and fixes most of its past debt, it still contains quite a handful of annoying bugs. These issues range from severe frame drops after interacting with a death idol to Sorun turning invisible and becoming unable to interact with anything, forcing a hard restart. There is a multitude of other minor annoyances as well but none of them are game breaking. Thankfully, there’s a day-one patch that should fix all the aforementioned issues.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death’s Gambit: Afterlife is the product of a dedicated team that wants to provide the best action experience possible. This revamped version offers plenty of new systems for returning fans and puts its best foot forward for new players. There’s great attention to balance in this Souls-like Metroidvania that supplies enough challenging encounters and deep customization for all players to enjoy. It looks like the Afterlife ain’t so bad after all.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">industria (full review) (in progress)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/industria.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="industria (full review) (in progress)" /><published>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-30T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/industria</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/30/industria.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/industria.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;industria&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: bleakmill&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: adventure fps&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 30, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: /10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: n/a hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Progress&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">young souls (full preview)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/28/youngsouls.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="young souls (full preview)" /><published>2021-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/28/youngsouls</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/28/youngsouls.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/youngsouls.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;young souls&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: 1p2p&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: beat ‘em up dungeon crawler&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes (local)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: fall 2021 (private preview)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $24.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, switch, playstation, xbox, stadia&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: /10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 2 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young Souls Preview: Featured on Adult Swim&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;By now, you’re probably tired of hearing the word “souls” in a game title. It must be another one of those games that take after the infamous Dark Souls! Surprisingly, the upcoming indie RPG Young Souls by developer 1P2P isn’t following that trend.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Through its unique art style that resembles comic books and cartoons, we experience an adventure through the determination of two young siblings. However, don’t let this description fool you, as Young Souls carries an action-driven narrative and additive mechanics that have my attention.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While playing a preview build of Young Souls, I was able to get a sneak peek of the narrative with some slice-of-life offerings, along with the chance to dive into the dungeon crawling and combat. When it comes to gameplay, there’s more depth than your typical indie beat ’em up as it contains a wide variety of customization options, complex combat mechanics, and side activities to partake in.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;First, we are introduced to orphaned twins Tristan and Jenn, fighting side by side in what appears to be a post-apocalyptic version of their world. After failing a battle against a giant enemy, they find themselves transported to the past before disaster strikes their city. The two end up in their bedroom, waking up to what seems to be a typical day. The twins are living with a work-a-holic professor, who has now become their adoptive father. I noticed that the twins have a potty mouth, especially Tristan, as he drops the f-bomb every other sentence. However, the relationship the professor shares with the twins is lighthearted and genuine, with the twins telling the professor not to forget to eat his meals and take care of his aging body. One day, they discover that the professor is missing. To their surprise, a strange portal in his laboratory has opened, revealing a mysterious world of goblins who threaten their very existence.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Without hesitation, Tristan and Jenn take up a pair of mysteriously readily available weapons and armor outside of the portal and step in, and this is where the combat happens. Interestingly, there’s a local co-op option, allowing you and a friend to team up. Of course, the game can also be played in single-player, with the option to switch between the siblings at any time. I wasn’t able to test out the co-op mode in this preview, but I am curious how the enemies will be balanced and scaled if you have two players in a dungeon. Playing solo allowed for two different builds to be utilized simultaneously, having Tristan be the tanker brawler while Jenn is the nimble DPS assassin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat has some depth, especially for a beat ’em up. You have a dodge, parry, and a whole slew of badass combos you can string up on the goblin baddies. Weapons and armor can be upgraded and looted from enemies and chests, making perfect sense for a dungeon crawler. However, the blocks and parries felt a little unpolished due to a very inconsistent timing window. Hopefully, the developers can hash that out in time for the full release.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Young Souls packs a lot of promise and color for a narrative-driven game that also identifies as a beat ’em up dungeon crawler. The fluid, action-packed presentation combined with the slice-of-life elements made me feel like I was playing through a comic book. It’s interestingly already out on Stadia but still has no definitive release date other than Fall 2021 on other platforms. I can’t wait to check out the full release to see how the story is fleshed out and beat up some more green baddies with the edgy pair of twins. Tristan might want to swear a bit less, though.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">neo: the world ends with you (full review) (in progress)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/28/ntwewy.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="neo: the world ends with you (full review) (in progress)" /><published>2021-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-28T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/28/ntwewy</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/28/ntwewy.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ntwewy.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;neo: the world ends with you&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: h.a.n.d.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 28, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $59.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, switch, playstation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: /10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: /10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: n/a hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Progress&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">diablo ii: resurrected (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/23/diablo2r.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="diablo ii: resurrected (full review)" /><published>2021-09-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/23/diablo2r</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/23/diablo2r.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/diablo2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;diablo ii: resurrected&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: vicarious visions, blizzard north&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 23, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $39.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, switch, playstation, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 30 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diablo II: Resurrected Review: Reborn From The Ashes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It takes a specific type of game for your hands to hurt from clicking and your eyes to burn from squinting. But those who understand this pain have probably played Diablo II. It encourages that “just one more run” mindset to build up an unkillable barbarian for hours on end. Twenty-one years later, I can do the same, now on a much bigger screen, a wireless optical mouse, and at 4K 60FPS.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diablo II: Resurrected is Blizzard’s attempt at remaking the original game that set the industry standard for isometric top-down action role-playing games. Resurrected delivers an almost identical experience to the legacy version, with updated visuals, a slew of quality-of-life changes, availability for consoles, and the inclusion of the Lord of Destruction DLC alongside two extra starting classes. Additionally, new surround sound audio is supported with a remastered soundtrack, and players have the option to switch to the legacy Diablo II with a single button click.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At its core, Diablo II is an action RPG, where you choose between one of seven classes and embark on a journey throughout a fantasy world, fighting monsters and building up your character with weapons, armor, and spells. It is the tried-and-tested dungeon-crawling formula where you replay on higher difficulties for a chance at better loot. There are 5 acts, 3 difficulties (Normal, Nightmare, Hell), online co-op, and PVP support for up to 8 players. Diablo II serves as the paradigm for more recent franchises such as Torchlight, Borderlands, and Path of Exile. It paved the way for countless indie titles to mirror its success.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Let’s be honest here; nobody plays Diablo for the story. The gameplay is all about min-maxing to build up a character through repeated dungeon runs to get the desired drop. Still, for those interested in the narrative, Diablo II takes place immediately after the first game’s events, where the hero attempts to contain Diablo within himself by plunging the Soulstone into his head. However, the hero is corrupted by Diablo and slowly loses control, becoming the Dark Wanderer. Thus, Diablo II follows the shoes of a new protagonist, chasing after the Dark Wanderer, to put an end to Diablo.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diablo II can be daunting at times, especially for newcomers, with the vast list of obtainable loot. The game doesn’t hold your hand either, never really introducing you to each class and how to build them, which often requires you to do a lot of reading or looking up a guide online. For example, while runewords were only introduced in the Lord of Destruction expansion of the original title, they are ever-present and vital in Resurrected.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Runes are drops from monsters that contain part of a word, which must then be inserted into gears that contain sockets to create runewords. Once placed, there’s no way to remove them without destroying them. Runewords grant extra properties to your gear, often greatly enhancing your build, such as 300% extra gold from monsters or +2 to class-specific skill levels.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps the greatest highlight of Diablo II: Resurrected is its complete visual overhaul. Upon booting it up for the first time, you are treated to an entirely remade cinematic in 4K graphics. Every act you complete rewards you with a CGI cutscene that is up to par with modern Blizzard titles. Moreover, Resurrected introduces 3D graphics compared to the completely 2D experience of the original. There are also improvements upon the original designs of visual effects of attacks and spells during gameplay, most noticeably the lightning and blizzard spells cast by the Sorceress class. Color palettes have been altered, bringing out more vibrant colorations and attention to focus points.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The core of Diablo II is untouched in Resurrected, which can serve as a nice dose of nostalgia or an outdated hindrance. Enemies and players still body block, frequently causing you to misclick and die if you can’t take the portal in time. Classes and gear have not been rebalanced, remaining faithful to the original builds that were viable in the legacy edition. Inventory management is still a headache, with no way to sort your items other than having to glance over each one manually. Item drops are insanely minuscule on the screen and depend on whether your mouse has hovered over the item at the right time.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This can all be overwhelming for new players, especially with so many actions happening on the screen at once. Oddly, there’s no way to zoom in or out of the map or scroll through it as the screen is centered around your character. Playing as a Necromancer, summoning 10 skeletons at your disposal lags performance significantly, especially if you are playing online with other people who are also playing Necromancer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, many quality-of-life changes have made the title more enjoyable and up to date with today’s standards. Still, picking up gold and other items of interest is both tedious and cumbersome, adding more clicks to your already tired fingers. While you still have to pick up items such as potions and gear manually, Resurrected now allows you to pick up gold by simply walking over it. Unfortunately, you still need to keep a keen eye for those rune and legendary drops in an online game. A shared stash has been introduced so you can easily transfer items between your multiple characters. Blizzard also expanded the size of said stashes, adding two additional tabs, allowing a total of 300 slots of storage space.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For the first time, in addition to the PC release, Diablo II: Resurrected is available on all consoles: Playstation, Xbox, and the Nintendo Switch. The game also supports cross-progression, allowing you to play with the same character should you choose to buy the game on multiple consoles. Unfortunately, cross-play is not supported, so you can’t play with your buddies on Playstation if you are on Xbox.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Diablo II: Resurrected is a faithful remaster of the original that defined the gold standard for the action role-playing genre. With 4K graphics, a higher frame-rate, fully remade cinematics, and a vast array of quality of life changes, this is an experience that serves as a love letter for nostalgic and veteran players and an enticing invitation for newcomers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">kena: bridge of spirits (full review) (in progress)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/21/kena.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="kena: bridge of spirits (full review) (in progress)" /><published>2021-09-21T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-21T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/21/kena</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/21/kena.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/kena.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;kena: bridge of spirits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: ember lab&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action adventure&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 21, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $39.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, playstation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: ps5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: /10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: /10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: n/a hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In Progress&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">tails of iron (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/tailsofiron.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="tails of iron (full review)" /><published>2021-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/tailsofiron</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/tailsofiron.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/tailsofiron.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tails of iron&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: odd bug studio&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: adventure rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 17, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $24.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, switch, playstation, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: ps5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bugs -0.5&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unbalanced -0.5&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;beautifully crafted, immersive world&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;engaging narrative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;large variety of weapon &amp;amp; gear customization&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;impactful combat with DualSense controller&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;diverse enemy types/movesets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;geralt of rivia xD&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of invincibility frames&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unbalanced, artificial enemy difficulty&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;some minor bugs&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 9 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tails of Iron Review: Return of the King&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It’s no news that rats are often seen as vermin and a nuisance, carrying parasites and spreading disease. Compared to their rodent cousin mice, rats are always portrayed as the lesser half. Humans have made their stance on these creatures clear throughout history, making mice swing swords and rescue princesses while rats kidnap animals and torture prisoners.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But Dan Robinson, team lead at Odd Bug Studio, the indie developers behind the adventure rpg Tails of Iron, couldn’t disagree more, couldn’t disagree more. Inspired by the affectionate and loving personalities of his real life rats, Robinson wanted to create a game that challenged the negative perception of rats! You play as Redgi, heir to the Rat throne, as you attempt to restore your broken kingdom after your father, the king, is slain by the ferocious Greenwart, leader of the United Frog Tribes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Tails of Iron takes heavy influence from Brian Jacques’ beloved Redwall and FromSoftware’s brutally punishing Dark Souls. The game, set in a dark fantasy medieval time period, combines an engaging fable with difficult yet rewarding combat. In terms of gameplay mechanics, it is most akin to other side-scrolling souls-likes such as Hollow Knight and Salt &amp;amp; Sanctuary, just without the acrobatic platforming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Odd Bug Studio does an immaculate job of creating a world that feels beautifully vast and looks incredibly detailed, despite it being only two dimensional. The environmental artists use 2D lights to create mood and depth, making landmarks and biomes unique and distinctive, each with its own hidden paths and secrets. The bold comic book line work breathes life into these anthropomorphized rodents and frogs as well as the environments. On the other hand, the dark moody atmosphere inspired by Grimm’s Fairy Tales not only appears charming on the outside but conveils dark undertones.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to audio and sound design, you immediately recognize a familiar voice. The game is narrated by Doug Cockle, the grizzled voice actor of Geralt of Rivia in The Witcher series. Although the characters converse wordlessly in dialogue composed of images and animations, the game succeeds in conveying the message. The crisp sounds of sword clashes, gunshots, footsteps, and townsfolk going about their day add mood,emotional depth, and life to Tails of Iron. The fanfare of the bards combined with howling wind and pouring rain brings realism to every corner you turn, from the Crimson Fort all the way to the Molshevik Republic. It made me chuckle to see Odd Bug Studio inject many silly easter eggs and plays on words into the game, such as Lans Alut, Hulk Molgan, and even Ratnor Rodentson, which refers to Thor Odinson for anyone curious.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unlike traditional role playing games, Tails of Iron does not follow stat allocation and progression such as vitality or dexterity. Instead, you are presented with an assortment of outfits and weapons, ranging from light and heavy armor sets to swords, axes, spears, and even guns! You can purchase them from vendors, ask BamBam the blacksmith to craft one via blueprints, or uncover them via exploration and defeating bosses. These armor sets offer resistances to different enemy types, so it is essential to change your loadout frequently. While there is no stamina meter, contrary to most soulslike games, Tails of Iron utilizes the weight system, where heavier armor may provide better protection, but at the cost of fat rolling. Different weapons also perform different movesets, where spears are quick and nimble but weaker, while hammers hit slower but harder. Maximum health is increased by bringing rare food items to RemRem the chef while he cooks you a hearty meal fit for a king.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is a refreshing number of enemy types and boss encounters, each with its own unique moveset and combat challenge. During certain missions, other anthropomorphic mammals also assist you on your journey, adding a nice sense of cooperative play to an otherwise solo game. Though as with most other soulslikes, you shouldn’t bother depending on them to be that helpful. You encounter more than just barbaric frogs on your journey, as you’ll face bugs, moles, the undead, and maybe something even more sinister! Exploration is also rewarding as you often come across treasure chests that contain hidden loot and secret boss fights to tackle. The main story is supplemented with a wide variety of side quests that you can find on announcement boards throughout different towns. These missions usually boil down to clearing grub nests, fighting strange beasts, or taking on arena duels with moles! Odd Bug Studio made each side quest replayable as you can embark on an already completed side quest for more rewards or if you’re itching to fight a boss again.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A big component of any action game, especially a soulslike, is the combat. Tails of Iron’s combat feels crisp and impactful due to audio and visual cues combined with the use of the DualSense haptic feedback. You have a one-handed weapon, a two-handed weapon, a ranged weapon, and a shield at your disposal at all times. You can also coat your weapon with poison consumables for an added edge in battle. Enemy attacks have a color-coded symbol that notifies you of the corresponding action that needs to be taken. White attacks must be blocked via a shield, red attacks must be dodged, and yellow attacks must be parried. Redgi can also heal via his potion flask that can be refilled by looting bugs or at designated barrels found throughout the world. Each boss has their own unique execution animation after being defeated, allowing for some satisfying relief after each fight. If you are to fall in battle, don’t worry as there is always a save bench not too far away!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There is definitely no shortage of soulslike games today, which makes it important for newer games to stand out in a sea of copycats. More so, it’s essential to implement the genre correctly. Unfortunately, Tails of Iron tries too hard to follow the shadow of Dark Souls that it fails to forge its own identity. Though the crux of the soulslike genre is demanding combat, genuine soulslike action should be fair and well-designed. Sadly, this is not the case with Tails of Iron. Dodges are mostly rendered useless as they fail to help you evade attacks. Certain boss moves stunlock you to the point where there is nothing you can do to evade damage, as they bombard you with three moves in succession. With an absence of invincibility frames, poor hitbox physics, and unbalanced enemy design, Tails of Iron feels like it was created by developers who haven’t actually played a FromSoftware game. In addition, there were also some weird bugs that I encountered, such as this camera zooming out bug that prevented me from moving Redgi or doing anything for that matter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Even though Tails of Iron undoubtedly contributes to the oversaturation of the soulslike genre, it is at its core a beautifully crafted indie game that tells a thought provoking narrative through the lens of some tiny mammals that are otherwise seen as house pests. The world, oozing with personality and begging to be explored, makes it clear that the developers have poured their heart into this game. Despite needing some bug bashing and combat repolishing, Tails of Iron is an under-rat-ed gem that will make a mighty fine addition to your indie game collection this year.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">aragami 2 (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/aragami2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="aragami 2 (full review)" /><published>2021-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/aragami2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/aragami2.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/aragami2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;aragami 2&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: lince works&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action stealth&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 17, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $39.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, playstation, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: ps5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 7.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 7/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 15 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aragami 2 Review: Shadows Wait Thrice&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In today’s gaming market, it’s quite rare to see games of the stealth genre, with nothing quite living up to Tenchu or the Metal Gear Solid series. It’s a very niche genre with a lot of waiting involved, so it has to be done right in order to be engaging and fun. Indie developer Lince Works ended that drought in 2016 with its debut title Aragami, an action-adventure stealth game following a ninja assassin with supernatural abilities.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, the long-awaited sequel has finally arrived, putting players a century after the events of Aragami. Though there are connections to the first game, Aragami 2 is a standalone sequel that follows the journey of Kurai, as he rises to become the last hope of the Kurotsuba clan after being threatened by a never-ending curse. While still staying mostly true to a stealth game, the sequel takes a shocking departure from many of the gameplay mechanics of the first game. The introduction of sword to sword combat, along with stealth assassinations, makes the game play like a combination of Ghost of Tsushima and Sekiro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Aragami are a collective of cursed individuals that are victims of a supernatural affliction that slowly robs them of their humanity, body, and mind. On top of this, they are also enslaved by the Akatsuchi Empire in their conquest of the Rashomon Valley, and it is up to you to stop them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As mentioned before, there are drastic differences between the sequel and the first game. While there is almost guaranteed death when spotted in Aragami 1, Aragami 2 allows for a welcome change of head-on combat instead. The main protagonist’s signature cape from the first game that is sapped of shadow essence energy every time you stand in light is replaced with a stamina bar instead. Level design is larger and free-roam exploration is incentivized with hidden collectibles and blueprints.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Aragami 2 is a fairly linear game, but instead of the story guided missions in Aragami 1, Aragami 2 introduces a central hub known as Kakurega Village, where you can select missions via a map, talk to friendly NPCs, unlock abilities, and purchase items. Each mission is still ranked by a letter for performance, with S being the highest tier ranking. The ranking system still works well as it incentivizes replayability for players wishing to challenge themselves for a better score. Completing missions earn you experience points that you can exchange for abilities in a skill tree. Scattered in each level are money bags you can collect to purchase consumables or cosmetic armor sets via the blacksmith in Kakurega Village.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lince Works also offers a respectable number of customization options into Aragami 2 by allowing you to purchase different dyes for your armor from a merchant found in the village. Rudimentary dye colors are unlocked as you progress through the story, but rarer colors must be found via hidden blueprints in each stage. The same goes for armor sets, as you get only a handful of armors available if you do only the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many of the design principles that crippled the first game make its way into the second one as well. A long, drawn out campaign bloated with fluff in the middle along with repetitive mission objectives makes Aragami 2 a chore to get through at times. You revisit the same maps upwards of seven to eight times as you cycle through the same loop of mission objectives: rescue or kidnap someone, fetch some items, or kill some enemies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Traversing each level, you can no longer shadow leap to areas of darkness, but instead to cliffs, ledges, windows, and rooftops. The grandiose scale of each map paired with this mechanic made each level feel like a playground I was swinging across.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The narrative of the first game was never its strong point, and the same goes for Aragami 2. The repetition of the middle bulk of the game brings the story to a halt, and it isn’t until the end of the game that new map layouts, enemy types, and mission objectives are introduced. The same goes for visual and audio design. For an indie title, the cel-shaded artwork is passable, with slightly better quality than the first title. Voice acting is abysmal and awkward, with characters speaking without their mouths moving in a language that I assume is supposed to be Japanese but doesn’t sound like it at all. For the most part, these details are excusable because the main focus is on the gameplay mechanics. On the topic of gameplay, Aragami 2 is definitely more ambitious than the first, with some things done well, and some things not so well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While your signature move, shadow kill, still makes an appearance in Aragami 2, there are a multitude of cool new skills and abilities you can unlock. These range from creating a cloud of stunning gas via lamp posts and summoning a shadow clone for distraction, to warp striking your enemy, akin to Noctis’s ability in Final Fantasy XV. By the end of the game, your entire arsenal of shadow powers allows for some very satisfying gameplay. Stringing together a slew of tightly knit executions without being spotted by an enemy always left a sly grin on my face. The versatility of the skill tree also greatly benefits the replayability of the game, allowing you to tackle previously completed missions with some new tricks up your sleeve.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Aragami 2 does offer the element of real time combat if you manage to break stealth, it doesn’t do it well at all. I did not expect the quality and polish of a triple A title such as Sekiro or Ghost of Tsushima, but the sword combat is flat out incompetent. The button input response was insanely inconsistent, where perfectly timed parries did nothing and enemies often hit me through walls, or broke out of my stunlock to one shot me. In the end, if I was spotted, I always opted to run away because of how unbalanced and unpolished the combat mechanics were. I understand that stealth should and still is the main focus of the game, but introducing a new mechanic and not implementing it well is just unacceptable.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the clunky combat, the enemy AI is pretty stupid. They don’t notice the splattered blood of their dead comrades right in front of them, and quickly lose interest in you after you jump onto a ledge, hilariously allowing you to backstab them within seconds. The entire mechanic of picking up a body and disposing of it is rendered useless because of the lackluster AI.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Despite its flaws, Aragami 2 is still an extremely fun game to play. I reckon it’d be more so with cooperative play, but I was not able to test that out in this review. Laying waste to unsuspecting enemies as you jump from rooftop to rooftop gives a sense of satisfaction that no other game can. Aragami 2 is a far departure from its predecessor, but one that I can respect as it stays true to its roots of being a stealth adventure game. With more environment and enemy variety, smarter AI, and a revamp of its combat system, Aragami 2 can very well stand at the forefront of indie titles.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">ni no kuni ii: revenant kingdom prince’s edition (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/nnk2.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="ni no kuni ii: revenant kingdom prince's edition (full review)" /><published>2021-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-09-17T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/nnk2</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/09/17/nnk2.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/nnk2.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;ni no kuni ii: revenant kingdom prince’s edition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: level-5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action adventure rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: september 17, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $59.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: switch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: switch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;n/a&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8.8/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 30 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ni no Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom Prince’s Edition Review&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Level-5 Inc. has always left a great impression on me, with the first games I played from them being the Dark Cloud series back in 2000. They have always managed to tell a captivating story combined with enjoyable gameplay mechanics, from then all the way to now, with their most recent Ni no Kuni series. While Ni no Kuni: Wrath of the White Witch puts you in the shoes of Oliver, who travels with his sidekick Drippy on a journey to save his mom, Ni No Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom has you play as Evan, the prince of Ding Dong Dell, travelling the world to gain alliances to create a nation free of war and full of love, after the advisor under his late father started a coup and took over his kingdom. With no direct correlation to the first game, Ni no Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom takes place a hundred years after the events of White Witch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ni no Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom Prince’s Edition is the newly released Switch Edition of the original game that was released back in 2018 on the Playstation 4 and PC. It contains the base game as well as all the additional content, which includes the Prince’s Equipment Package, The Adventure Pack DLC, The Lair of the Lost Lord DLC and The Tale of a Timeless Tome DLC.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The world presented in Ni No Kuni II sometimes blurs the lines between the real world and fantasy world. The game starts the player off in the shoes of Roland, a president of some country on Earth, only to be decimated by what seems to be a nuclear bomb. He wakes up in the magical kingdom of Ding Dong Dell, in the chambers of prince Evan. Evan’s kingdom is now under the control of usurper Mausinger, and the prince finds himself driven out. Roland and Evan set out on a journey to create a kingdom where there is no war and everyone can live happily after. Though it sounds sappy and cheesy, the narrative of Ni no Kuni II happens to have some really emotional moments as well as exploring themes of politics and technology. It not only shows the character development of Evan, but also the maturity and growth of him as a young adult, which makes it the perfect example of a coming-of-age story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are four kingdoms that comprise Ni no Kuni II’s open-world, with the fifth one being Evan’s newly created one, called Evermore. Visually and aurally speaking, Ni no Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom does an impeccable job combining art designed by former employees of Studio Ghibli themselves with an evocative soundtrack by Joe Hisaishi. Hisaishi-san does a fantastic job creating a score that goes from cheery and lighthearted to somber and melancholic at the right moments that highlight the undertones of the narrative. Every new area you explore presents a distinct theme and culture. From the sandy dunes of Sky Pirates Bay to the watery shores of Hydropolis, there’s color bursting out of every corner of Ni no Kuni II. However, while there is great voice acting in important cutscenes, lesser important dialogue options with text bubbles are accompanied by weird mumbles and grunts, making the game a little less immersive.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Combat in Ni no Kuni II might deceive you with its simplicity at first, but runs deeper than meets the eye. While the combat in the first Ni no Kuni was more akin to a tactical turn based RPG, Ni no Kuni II’s combat takes a more free-roam hack-and-slash approach similar to that of the Tales series. The real-time combat introduced in Ni no Kuni II allows you to control one character at a time while other party members fight on. Actions consist of attacking, defending, dodge rolling as well as executing special abilities. You have a party of three characters of whom you can switch between at any time. Each party member has a different moveset and ability, so it is intended for you to switch it up depending on the combat scenario. The twist that Ni no Kuni II adds is the introduction of Higgledies, which are little creatures that can be assigned to perform certain actions during battle such as buffing a party member, healing, or attacking the enemy. When you deal damage with a particular weapon, it will build up a meter that can be used when full to execute a buffed up skill, which further adds complexity and variety to the combat mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While battles are fluid and crisp in Ni no Kuni II, there is often a lack of challenge, as fights are often more than forgiving and trivial when it comes to making mistakes. This isn’t inherently a bad thing though, as forgiving combat allows for more trial and error to find a playstyle most fun for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the core of it, Ni no Kuni II is an open world JRPG, but it also is a building simulator where you get to reconstruct buildings, farm resources, research technology, and recruit people. Those who are familiar with the building mechanic in the Dark Cloud series will feel right at home with Ni no Kuni II. The aspect of kingdom building ties in so perfectly with the narrative as it ties in many of the ambitious systems the game is trying to accomplish. Different citizens you recruit also specialize in different fields, ranging from weapon crafting to magic brewing. Depending on which facilities you build and people you recruit, you can acquire a variety of buffs such as improved experience gain, new abilities and faster movement speed. The kingdom building mechanic is directly tied with your battle system, so the more time you invest into building your kingdom, the more advantage you will have in combat.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As with many games ported to the Switch that end up suffering from performance issues, Ni no Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom is no different. The frame rate seems to suffer slightly when lots of action is going on the screen, such as moments of heated combat or hectic boss encounters. Visual quality also does not look as crisp and polished as its version on Playstation or PC. Playing in both handheld and docked mode, performance seemed to be better playing on the big screen rather than in bed. But for the most part, there were no game breaking bugs or crashes and nothing detracted from my overall enjoyment of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ni No Kuni II: Revenant Kingdom Prince’s Edition is an excellent addition to gaming on the go. It’s a feature packed port on the Switch that not only delivers a heartwarming story following Evan and a beautiful musical score, but also impactful combat and kingdom building mechanics. While the Switch version doesn’t look as good or perform as well as it would on the PC or Playstation, the portability factor makes up for the limited Switch hardware. There’s never a shortage of things to do in Ni No Kuni II, with no amount of content seen as fluff and loads of incentive to venture out and explore. This wonderfully crafted JRPG is a must play for veterans and newcomers of the genre alike.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>