<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-08-23T08:08:34-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">henry y.</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">lamentum (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/23/lamentum.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="lamentum (full review)" /><published>2021-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-23T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/23/lamentum</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/23/lamentum.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/lamentum.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;lamentum&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: obscure tales&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: survival horror&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: august 31, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $15.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, playstation, xbox, switch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;was it scary? yes +1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;immersive atmosphere and worldbuilding&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenging, thought provoking puzzles&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;engaging narrative with deep lore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tension building save system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;great music and sound design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;humble price point&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;hard difficulty curve (not a con, but not for everyone)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clunky combat&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 14 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lamentum Review: Unforgiving Tale of Lovecraftian Sorrow&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pixel art and horror? At first glance, these two categories seem ill suited for each other, yet Lamentum is more haunting because it’s not trying to scare you with photo-realistic ray-traced graphics. Two-person developer team Obscure Tales serves up a dreary survival horror experience in the form of Lamentum, a pixel art survival-horror game that takes place in New England in the mid-18th century and subtly reminds me of Yuppie Psycho mixed with Resident Evil and Silent Hill. Fittingly, this game’s name refers to lament, a passionate expression of grief or sorrow, which is a prominent theme of the game. You play as Victor, a young aristocrat that steps foot into the ominous Grau Hill Mansion, searching desperately to find a cure for his sickly wife.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When your wife’s affliction cannot be cured by traditional medicine, you seek out a strange count who is a master of forgotten sciences and possesses knowledge beyond comprehension. The destiny of Victor and his wife are now in the hands of Edmond Steinrot, and a place only spoken of in whispers, Grau Hill. You soon find out that Victor is blinded by love and naive to the fullest extent. When he wakes up after a seemingly normal night’s sleep in the mansion, Victor discovers that everyone has disappeared, and instead, grotesque and cosmic creatures stalk the halls and corridors. Though his world is literally turned upside down, like in Stranger Things, Victor will stop at nothing to uncover the truth behind Grau Hill and save his beloved partner. The motifs of grief and sorrow go beyond just the protagonist himself, but encompass the entire history and mystery surrounding Grau Hill and its inhabitants.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Visually speaking, the pixel art does great justice to the Victorian era aesthetic and deformed entities inspired by HP Lovecraft’s celestial creatures. There is never a shortage of creature variety as they get progressively malformed the deeper into the nightmare you go. Though there is no voice acting, the ambience invokes despair through music and sound design, the dark heart of the game. The duo developers are collaborating with Black Light Sound, a small Spain-based composer. They do a fantastic job piecing together the composition that includes off-putting cues in the presence of danger, violin strings playing violently during a boss encounter, and the calm melody of the safe room. The eerie paintings on the walls and bloodstained statues combined with tense change in audio always send a chill down my spine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Finding clues around the mansion and garden as to where your missing wife might be, you progress by acquiring a variety of weapons to use that contain a kitchen knife, knight’s blade, pistol and blunderbuss. Along the way, you are also presented with a variety of puzzles that are very reminiscent of old-school survival horror games. You are required to piece together cryptic tablets, dodge spikes, and perform a little bit of Victorian era chemistry experiments as well! There are also locked doors labeled with certain symbols that need to be revisited later when the appropriate key is obtained and dark areas where a lantern is needed to illuminate your surroundings. The immersion with the atmosphere of the game is well maintained as Lamentum does not hold your hand when it comes to solving these puzzles and riddles. Oftentimes, you need to do some thinking, exploring and digging before you figure out what to do next.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fitting right in with the unforgiving nightmare that is Grau Hill, Lamentum is both hardcore and difficult. Inventory space is meager, health points are low, ammo is limited, and enemies hit hard; you’ll be seeing the “You Died” screen as often as you would in a Dark Souls game. The combat of the game is a bit clunky as there is a long delay between choosing to attack and actually landing your attack. Though this might have been intended by the developers, fighting usually ended with me prematurely swinging to land my attack when the enemies entered the hitbox. There is no auto save, and manual save is limited and can only be done in specific safe rooms with consumable inkwells. These safe rooms contribute to the immersion of the game while also allowing Victor to write down his thoughts and remember the events that transpired before his nightmare. Fans of Resident Evil will recognize both the mechanics as well as the background music playing in the safe rooms, a dreary yet peaceful melancholic piano theme. Choosing between fight or flight and learning to save the game will be essential in progressing through the game. One thing worth commending is that there are always enough inkwells, ammunition, and healing items scattered throughout so that the game strikes an equilibrium between challenging and unbalanced. Due to its difficulty curve, manifestation of disempowerment, and lack of direction, Lamentum is not a game that everyone can finish, but a harrowing experience that every horror fan should have.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the game is not replayable in the traditional sense that different dialogue options offer different outcomes, there are four different endings you can achieve based on your decisions nearing the end of the game, including a true secret ending. Additional secrets, characters, and collectibles can also be discovered if you have the itch to explore and learn more about the lore of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Lamentum embodies all the elements of a good survival horror game: helplessness, isolation, tension, uncertainty, and fear. In addition, it has every feature one would want in an old-school survivor horror game: grotesque monsters, an arsenal of weapons, brain-teasing puzzles, limited saves, free-roam exploration, and multiple endings. Lamentum is equal parts frightening as it is enticing, serving up a scintillating world filled with Lovecraftian horrors and remnants of old school Resident Evil and Silent Hill. It is a must-play for any fans of the genre looking for challenging gameplay, deep mythos, and an alluring narrative.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">garden story (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/18/gardenstory.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="garden story (full review)" /><published>2021-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-18T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/18/gardenstory</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/18/gardenstory.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/gardenstory.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;garden story&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: picogram&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action rpg / life simulator&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: august 11, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc/switch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 11/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;phenomenal soundtrack, go grahm nesbitt!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;strong, inspiring narrative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;great variety of gameplay mechanics that get sprinkled in at a good pace&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;outstanding pixel art thats cute and inviting&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clunky combat, iffy hitboxes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;punishing in the beginning (not a con, but may be turn off for some players)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;more focus on combat than farming (not a con, but may be turn off for some players)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 10 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garden Story Review: Grapeness Awaits&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do you ever get tired of the burdens of mundane life? Are you ready to embark on a journey graper than yourself? Your home has been desecrated by the mysterious Rot, and Guardian Plum has left your town, appointing you the new Guardian of Spring Hamlet. You are Concord, Guardian Grape, and the destiny of The Grove now lies in your tiny little stems! Garden Story, the newest game by solo developer Picogram, contains strong scents of Harvest Moon and My Time at Portia due to its beautifully hand-drawn pixel art and delicate musical score. However, upon closer inspection, Garden Story is more of a hybrid between a Zelda lite and Stardew Valley, with gameplay elements from an action RPG and a life simulator. The game deliciously weaves together themes of community, self-discovery, and personal identity.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If it wasn’t clear already, you play as an adorable, stumpy, round, purple grape, who has spent its entire life in the Kindergarden, maintaining a single vine with the life essence of The Grove known as Dew. All the inhabitants of Garden Story live in The Grove, home to a massive tree full of mana and partitioned into four towns based on the seasons: Spring Hamlet, Summer Bar, Autumn Town, and Winter Glade. One day, Guardian Plum lets you out of the Kindergarden and informs you of his upcoming departure. He appoints you to be his successor, teaching you the basics of combat and how to help out neighboring towns. But you soon discover, unfortunately, that the very lifeline of The Grove is threatened by a dark force known as The Rot, and it is up to you to help rebuild each of the aforementioned towns and re-establish their communication with each other.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many games have you traveling from place to place without giving you opportunities to feel a sense of ownership. In Garden Story, however, you have a place to call home in each village that you visit! The main gameplay loop revolves around talking to main characters to progress the narrative and interacting with a bulletin board next to your house that assigns you daily quests to level up and rebuild the village. Some main quests require your village to be at a certain level before becoming available, so it is in your best interest to complete some every day! Of course, the higher your village’s level, the better items the shops will sell as well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Daily quests are divided up into three categories: combat in which you defeat some Rot; building. where you rebuild a bridge or fix a fence; and gathering where you collect resources to donate to the village. Though straightforward, the daily tasks vary from day to day so they aren’t mundane and tedious. In addition to the aforementioned main quests and daily tasks, there are also side quests from various characters found in the world and challenging dungeons to explore. Picogram did a fantastic job instilling a sense of hope, belonging, and community by deepening your connection with the inhabitants of The Grove.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At first glance, Garden Story seems to focus heavily on resource gathering, town-building, and farming. However, there is a prominent focus on combat in the game that is reminiscent of vanilla Dark Souls. Unfortunately, the combat is a bit clunky as it feels slow and unresponsive. Hitboxes are also wonky and minuscule. Some enemies are weirdly unbalanced, especially the mini ooze Rots that deal on-contact damage and are extremely difficult to hit. As you fight the Rot throughout your journey, you have a stamina bar that depletes every time you swing your weapon or dodge roll. You are given a shield to use too, but I found myself rarely using it, if ever. Combat is surprisingly challenging initially and gets progressively lenient because you start with only 3 hit points and 2 stamina bars. Every time you defeat a boss, you are rewarded with a permanent increase to your hit points and stamina bar. Furthermore, as you explore, achieve weapon mastery, and help out townsfolk, you collect memories that can be equipped to further customize your playstyle, with memories that may further increase your health and stamina or give you better luck or healing potency. Alongside the combat, there are also mango-nificent puzzles to complete that keep you engaged. The puzzles start simple but get gradually more arduous. Still, they are never un-raisin-able!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As you progress further into the game, every new village you visit will introduce you to a new gameplay mechanic that keeps tasks fresh and exciting. For example, by the time you get to the second town, you receive the dowsing rod that you can use to fish items out of the ocean and rip otherwise unbreakable shells off of Rot enemies. Then, when you reach the Winter Glade, you receive a pair of snazzy ice skates! Building structures and gardening resources also get introduced later on to scratch that Stardew Valley itch. Though more low-key and not as emphasized as combat, the ability to actually create structures and cultivate plants further drives the theme of belonging and community. The more you customize your town, the more lively and personal it begins to feel. Garden Story is really about building your home. A fiery maraschino cherry even offered to stand guard in front of my house at night to fight off any Rot that might wander in!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To be honest, Garden Story and I got off on the wrong foot in the beginning. The tutorial wasn’t that helpful, the gameplay menus were overwhelming, combat didn’t feel smooth, and the PC key bindings were awkwardly placed. However, once I took the time to appreciate the luscious world and the fruits of my labor, the title began to feel zen. By the end of it, I couldn’t help but feel proud of Concord’s advancement from an isolated grape gardener to a world-saving guardian.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On top of all those aforementioned points, there’s nothing better to do than relaxing in The Grove’s inviting atmosphere, conversing with my frog friend Rana, cultivating gardens, and listening to the cherry-sweet music of the Summer Bar. I cannot express enough love for the original soundtrack composed by Grahm Nesbitt. It truly immersed me into the plum-forgettable world to the point where I played the OST in the background as I wrote this review.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Garden Story isn’t necessarily about what you do, since you mostly take on simple and tedious tasks. Instead, the game is about the people you meet along the way, the lives you touch, the connections you make, and ultimately not forgetting about your roots, no plum intended. It has honestly been a while since I’ve been emotionally moved by a game this sweet, especially one paired with a beautiful soundtrack. If you are looking for a cozy world-building game with some combat and a whole lot of charm and whimsy, then The Grove welcomes you like a home away from home. Concord, you’re truly one-in-a-melon, and you did a grape job raisin me!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">glitchpunk (early access review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/11/glitchpunk.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="glitchpunk (early access review)" /><published>2021-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-11T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/11/glitchpunk</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/11/glitchpunk.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/glitchpunk.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;glitchpunk (early access)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: dark lord&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: top down sci-fi action twinstick shooter&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: august 11, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 3/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bugs - 2&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;good variety of weapons/hacking modules&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;karma system with different gangs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;branching narrative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;no manual or auto save&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extremely long loading screens&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unbalanced gameplay&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;infinite movement drift (not a keyboard issue)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;key bind menu glitched out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gun shooting &amp;amp; car driving is insanely clunky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;so many other bugs…&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 4.75/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: never (at least not until 1.0 release)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 2 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glitchpunk Early Access Review: Too Many Glitches, Too Little Punk&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For fans of open-world retro Grand Theft Auto-style games, Glitchpunk is made to relive the chaotic glory emitted by those titles. The game markets itself as a top-down cyberpunk twin-stick shooter, and it manages to feel like a mashup between Hotline Miami and old-school GTA set in a futuristic dystopia. You play as an android bounty hunter gifted with a special trait called “glitch.” It enables you to go against your programming and become sentient, allowing you to define your own destiny.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Glitchpunk contains many hallmarks from Grand Theft Auto, including the freedom to basically do anything you want: kill anyone, steal cars, etc. However, law enforcement will be sent to detain you if you commit too many crimes and won’t stop until you escape or are dead.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;An interesting element the game introduces is the reputation you have with the numerous gangs rough-housing the city. Doing quests for one gang may decrease your reputation for another, leading to different dialogue options and narratives. There are also different cyber modules you can purchase and install that allow you to hack anyone you see.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;However, Glitchpunk begins with a very rocky start, living up to its title in the most literal sense. Not only does the game suffer from lengthy loading screens and constant frame drops, but it is also riddled with an array of technical glitches and bugs. For instance, I encountered infinite movement drift that forced my character to move infinitely upwards or downwards, and I can clarify that it wasn’t an issue with my keyboard.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To top it all off, a never-ending loop of “Press Key to Bind” notifications popped up when I navigated the gameplay menus, even when I tried to quit the game. All of these technical issues resulted in force quits and hard reboots. How unfortunate is it that I took more time trying to get the game to work rather than actually playing it?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In addition to the aforementioned technical issues, the gameplay mechanics are janky and unpolished. There is no auto or manual save, which essentially turns the game into a roguelike as you have to complete the entire experience in one sitting, or else you will lose all of your progress. The gameplay is also exceptionally unbalanced. If you so much as bump into a cop, you will immediately be shot down and killed in seconds. Doing so will respawn you at a nearby hospital, stripping you of all the equipment you purchased and a good chunk of your money for “hospital fees.”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;At the launch of Early Access, there is only one city of the planned four available. However, a roadmap is available that highlights more guns, modules, cars, and additional cities will release over the next 6-8 months.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I typically try to play through an entire game to form a proper criticism of it; unfortunately, due to the extremely buggy mess that is Glitchpunk, I was unable to play for more than a few hours. There must be some curse on cyberpunk-themed games that leaves the genre in an unplayable state. Even for Early Access, this game needs a lot of work, and hopefully, the developers invest time into this experience. There is no doubt that Glitchpunk pays homage to classic Grand Theft Auto titles and holds undeniable potential, but it is not a game I can recommend checking out in its current condition. I hope for nothing but the best for a solid 1.0 release from the developers.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">last stop (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/10/laststop.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="last stop (full review)" /><published>2021-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-10T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/10/laststop</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/10/laststop.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/laststop.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;last stop&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: variable state&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: narrative adventure game&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: july 22, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $24.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, playstation, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;strong thought provoking narrative&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;great character development&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rich atmosphere and sound design&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;walking simulator&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dialogue options make no difference&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rushed ending/climax&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 6.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 5 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Stop Review: Superb Narrative Hindered by Non-Gameplay&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;What would you do if you were given the choice of improving your own life at the cost of another’s? The moral dilemma and the gap between selfish and selfless are brought to light by the newest game from developer Variable State. Last Stop is a supernatural sci-fi drama adventure game focused mainly on the narrative that feels like a crossover episode between Doctor Who and The Twilight Zone. However, the game feels like a story that could’ve been told without the video game mechanics. Last Stop is a game about unremarkable people embarking on extraordinary events. The five-hour adventure is split into three separate tales that revolve around three characters that have nothing in common until they ultimately intermingle to form a wider plot.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The prologue of Last Stop begins in a London subway station in 1982. Two teenagers are being chased by police through maintenance corridors when they encounter a mysterious man in a brown suit. The man opens a door behind him, revealing an otherworldly portal, and beckons the two to step in. While Samantha walks through the portal, Peter, the boy, chickens out and is arrested.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Fast forward twenty years, the three stories play out over the course of seven chapters. You are free to choose who’s story arc to play first, per chapter. First, there’s John Smith, a disorganized single dad struggling to make ends meet. His story begins when a curse leads him and his neighbor Jack to swap bodies, Freaky Friday style. Then, we have Meena Hughes, an unfaithful, career-obsessed woman who has ruined her relationship with her father, husband, and son. She removes herself further when she is pressured to compete for a promotion she has been working so hard towards. Lastly, we have Donna Adeleke, an ordinary London high-schooler struggling with her home life and friendships. She becomes an accidental kidnapper after trailing a suspicious neighbor that doesn’t seem entirely human.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The developer does a brilliant job with its art style, story-telling, and sound design. The design is minimalistic, focusing on the characters rather than the backdrop. Last Stop manages to capture the chemistry and personality of the cast through their interactions and expressions. There are a few mishaps due to awkward animations and words not matching the movements of each character’s mouth, but there’s a good mix of strong writing and voice acting to keep players engaged.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The gameplay, on the other hand, is extremely limited by scope. These elements include choosing dialogue options, walking, quick-time events, and the occasional puzzle or mini-game. The mini-games are refreshing and include events such as putting books back on a shelf and piecing together broken ceramic ware. But, unfortunately, in most cases, the interactions you have as a player are largely meaningless and inconsequential, to the point where it feels like a chore to make a character jog faster or scoop cereal and drink coffee.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While my interest remained in the story, the game requires you to walk long distances without any real reason. From your house to school, to the store, to the office. Sometimes, it’s not obvious which way you should be walking, so you end up walking into an invisible wall before realizing you were going in the wrong direction. Further, any dialogue choices, whether to make a particular character cold and harsh or warm and endearing, make absolutely no difference in the outcome of the narrative. This causes the experience to really fall out of touch with its gameplay elements.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The journey to get to the meat of the narrative ends up being a predictable ride. When the paths finally connect, Last Stop does a great job tying up loose ends while leaving others intentionally untied for the player’s interpretation. There’s a fantastic authenticity in the characters as I found each of them relatable. The moral and existential decisions they are faced with are still lingering in my mind. Although a sci-fi narrative, the focus is always on the ordinary lives instead of the supernatural element. Variable State also did a great job intermingling characters of different personalities: Meena being a logical, ruthless, alpha, Donna being an innocent teenager, and John being a comic relief and an overall goofball. Although the final chapter is enjoyable due to its twists and turns, the ending is paced awkwardly, weighing on the entire experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Last Stop serves up a strong narrative, mixing existentialism with the lives of ordinary people, but it forgets to be a game at some points. The interaction and story bits keep you invested at the cost of choices and navigation segments that do nothing for the adventure. At its best, Last Stop should be enjoyed as a casual narrative-focused experience, but asking anything more of it may have you exiting before the end of the line.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">death trash (early access review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/05/deathtrash.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="death trash (early access review)" /><published>2021-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-08-05T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/05/deathtrash</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/08/05/deathtrash.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/deathtrash.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;death trash (early access)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: crafting legends&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: isometric open-world action rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: august 5, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, mac (later on playstation/xbox/switch)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;amazing art direction/style&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;deep mythos inspired by Lovecraft&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rich rpg elements&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;meat, puke, brains!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;clunky dodge roll system&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;inventory management&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;random mines everywhere!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8.1/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 5 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death Trash Early Access Review: A Grotesque Wasteland of Cosmic Flesh&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When it comes to modern day gaming aesthetics, a large focus has been on utilizing photorealism to make worlds look as clean-cut and pristine as possible. However, developers Crafting Legends decided to go the opposite route. Their upcoming game, Death Trash, is set in a mucky, filthy, gory, and trash-ridden world filled with mystery and Lovecraftian secrets, and I’m loving it!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Death Trash is an open-world, post-cyberpunk, post-apocalyptic isometric pixelated rpg with an emphasis on delivering a strong narrative. The story takes place on Planet Nexus, centuries after The Bleeding. Humanity has been driven into hiding as bloodthirsty machinery and otherworldly creatures scour the planet to terminate any remaining survivors. You are cast out of a safe underground community, for reasons unknown other than there is an eldritch sickness growing inside of your body. You are told to never return or you will face immediate termination.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Before being thrown into the dystopian wasteland, you learn the basics of movement, interaction, combat, and stealth in a training facility that acts as the tutorial to the game’s mechanics. In Death Trash, you are free to do whatever you want and go wherever you want, although you will face the consequences of the choices you make. For example, I’m really interested in seeing how attacking friendly main quest givers may affect your progression in the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Character creation takes from classic role playing games, where you can choose any combination of body types, outfits, among other customizations. You have a variety of core stats that dictate your playstyle. Hardiness increases your health and resistances. Strength allows the use of better melee weapons while finesse allows the use of better ranged weapons. Occultism allows you to use abilities that communicate with the flesh. Cybertech allows you to use implants and tech abilities. Empathy unlocks dialogue options that influence interactions with characters found in the world. In addition, you also have skills that range from animalism to pickpocketing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although combat is quite simplistic, with your typical melee attack and dodge, there’s the added versatility of firearms and cyber augmentations as well. However, the dodge roll system is a little wonky and you can quickly become overwhelmed and killed by how many and how hard enemies hit, even on the easiest difficulty. Fortunately, there is freedom in how you approach combat, as you can take a more tactical approach by sneaking past enemies via stealth.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Meat, flesh, and puke play a significant role in Death Trash. Not long after you venture out into the wasteland, you meet a giant “Flesh-Kraken” that requests you to find a friend for it. Scattered throughout the world are lumps of flesh that you can either attack or tame, depending on how you allocate your skills. Meat’s importance is further revealed through the townsfolk’s obsession with it, as well as its role as a “potion” that restores your health when eaten. Heck, there’s even a location called Puke Bar, where you can get drunk and puke alongside other fellow outcasts. Some ancient machinery also operates when fueled with your “bio-lubricant”, or puke. Did I mention you can also puke on demand?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The game clearly draws inspiration from games such as Fallout and folklore from HP Lovecraft, but it manages to forge its own identity, weaving together a mysterious narrative, challenging gameplay and a whole lot of flesh. In the current landscape of gaming, where most games feel derivative, Death Trash feels unique given its distinctive art direction, deep mythos, and rich rpg elements. Death Trash has a lot of meat on the bone for anyone craving a fleshy and juicy treat. After all, one person’s Trash may be another’s treasure. Having been in development for six years, the game is finally making its celestial debut in Early Access on Steam on August 5, 2021.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I was very impressed and intrigued by the Early Access version of Death Trash, which is roughly one third of the final story campaign. I can’t wait to see what the developers have in store for the full release in 2022.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">the ascent (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/29/ascent.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="the ascent (full review)" /><published>2021-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-29T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/29/ascent</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/29/ascent.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ascent.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;the ascent&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: neon giant&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: isometric top-down twin-stick action rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: july 29, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $29.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 3/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lots of bugs -2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unbalanced -1&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;great worldbuilding - cyberpunk aesthetic (visuals &amp;amp; audio)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;good variety of guns, augmentations, tactical gear, armor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;decent loading times&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bugs: invisible enemies, broken input keys, buggy hitboxes, buggy scenes, incorrectly spelled subtitles, infinite exp&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;frame drops when lots of action (ie. explosion/lots of enemies)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tedious amounts of walking, backtracking with little incentive/reward (no sprint functionality)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unbalanced/insane difficulty spikes for solo play (enemies are just damage sponges)&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;co-op is broken, multiple crashes, laggy/zooming around map, shared loot, no public matchmaking&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;limited enemy variety - lots of re-used enemy types&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;false promises - loading screens (not seamless), beat the game + side missions in 12 hours (promised 15-20 hours at least)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 5.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 12 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Ascent Review: Underwhelming Cyberpunk Hype&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Viewed from a distance, Veles, the cyberpunk planet dominated by The Ascent Group’s arcology, looks like a massive and sprawling metropolis filled with life and promise. A closer look reveals the chaos and confusion that ensue in the wake of the collapse of the Ascent Group, the mega corporation that owns everyone. You play as an indent, or an indentured worker, who must ascend to the top of the social hierarchy and figure out what really happened. The Ascent is a solo and cooperative open world, isometric, top-down, twin-stick action rpg.  Like other games of the same genre, The Ascent may seem like the long-awaited fulfillment of the promise of a great cyberpunk experience. However, when experienced from up close, players will find that The Ascent is far from that, and will soon be forgotten in the shadows of its failed predecessors.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Veles is a vivid and intricate city, filled with neon signs, flashy billboards, futuristic hover cars, monolithic skyscrapers, and creatures from all over the galaxy. Neon Giant does a fantastic job creating a game drenched in atmosphere, weaving together conversations of passersby going about their day, billboard announcements over the speaker, endless drops of pouring rain, and neo noir electro synth soundtrack in the background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though Veles may have you in awe with its remarkable visual and auditory aesthetic at first, you will soon feel like you are wandering tediously in a lifeless static world. To put open world and isometric rpg together is a bold undertaking. Though the world is filled with NPCs, Veles is nothing but a giant landscape of reused assets and enemy types. You can only interact with a very limited number of objects and people. These include NPCs that assign quests or exchange hard-coded dialogue with you, as well as shops in dedicated safe zones. In addition, you are free to shoot and kill neutral citizens, but it is nothing more than a gimmick. You don’t gain experience points and gold, or trigger any sort of karma system. Fast travel options like the taxi and subway system, are either too expensive or too limited, leaving you to walk, without even a sprint option, five to ten minutes just to progress the story.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The main story of The Ascent is mediocre, and is nothing to write home about. You play as the classic silent protagonist doing various jobs for various corporations as you uncover what really happened to The Ascent Group. You experience everything from life in the slums all the way up to skyline suites enjoyed by the rich. On the other hand, side missions are mundane and monotonous, where most are just simple fetch quests or killing said person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Neon Giant introduces some refreshing gameplay elements. Being a twin stick shooter, The Ascent offers the ability to aim both high and low on enemy targets, with a crouch/cover system behind various objects and structures found in the world. Being an rpg as well, the game offers character customization and skill trees, including cyberware augmentations and the ability to hack using a cyberdeck. There is a delightful variety of different weapons, tactical gear, and augmentations to find and utilize. These vary from pistols and shotguns to miniguns, spider bots and even your own mech robot to control! The amount of customization and differentiation in gear is very robust and promotes different playstyles, especially in co-op. Loot, on the other hand, is preset, not randomized, and often very underwhelming. Most of the time, whatever loot you collect is best sold for cash in the shops as leveling up weapons is only possible via a rare currency found in the world. In addition, old bosses become regular mobs and enemy types end up being reused a lot. Most are not worth killing because they drop little experience and gold. Exploration is also bland because oftentimes, you will walk several minutes with the intent of finding loot, only to discover that it is locked behind a higher “hack” level or is just cash or an item you already own. There is very limited replayability of this game as it is not driven by loot and there is no new game plus.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a game that markets itself heavily on cooperative play, The Ascent not only fails to meet the most rudimentary of expectations for an online game, but also lacks substantially in solo offline play. To put it simply, the co-op function is broken. Multiple crashes ensue after hosting or joining an online session to the point where the multiplayer aspect of the game is not only unenjoyable, but unplayable. In the brief minutes in which the online session does not crash, bugs riddle the game; one player zooms across the map at lightning speed, and enemies that are visible to one player are invisible to another. In addition, there is no option of public matchmaking yet there is the functionality to kick players from your session. If you’re only playing with friends, why would you want to kick them out? The loot, aside from important key items, is also shared among all players, which promotes unhealthy and often unfair multiplayer experiences. Moving forward, the solo player experience doesn’t bode so well either. An atrocious number of enemies that are basically just damage sponges come at you while you are tasked to point defend or survive X number of minutes, making the game extremely unbalanced.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Many sci-fi and cyberpunk genre fan’s have kept The Ascent on their radar, especially after being disappointed by recent similar releases. After being delayed as an Xbox Series X launch title, the game still isn’t polished at all. Unfortunately, the game is nevertheless infested with bugs that include but are not limited to the inability to shoot any gun, invisible enemies (there are actual invisible enemies whose silhouettes you can see in the game), constant frame drops when there is lots of action, incorrect hit boxes, and even an infinite exp glitch. The Ascent also falls victim to the cycle of false advertising and marketing. The game is said to be “seamless, with essentially no loading screens”, yet the elevator, taxi, and subway rides that cut to black essentially act as replacement loading screens. The developers promise that “playing through the Main Missions will land you somewhere around 15 to 20 hours.” I was able to complete all the main missions and a handful of side missions in 12 hours, with a good chunk of that being straight up walking and retrying the insanely unbalanced single player boss encounters.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In theory, a co-op, loot based isometric rpg like The Ascent has the potential of being a great cyberpunk-themed game that you can play with a group of friends. The game’s world building is extremely appealing visually and aurally. However, its unsatisfying, and often unrewarding opportunities for exploration, lack of replayability, broken cooperative play, bugs, and unbalanced artificial enemy difficulty make it very difficult to appreciate its positive elements. There are also many quality of life changes that need to be addressed such as a lack of a manual save, no sprint functionality, tutorials randomly re-appearing, and Steam achievements not popping. It is sad to say that The Ascent is another over-hyped cyberpunk game that is all fluff, and no substance.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">tribes of midgard</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/27/tribesofmidgard.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="tribes of midgard" /><published>2021-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-27T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/27/tribesofmidgard</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/27/tribesofmidgard.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/midgard.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;tribes of midgard&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: norsfell&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: roguelike tower defense survival rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: yes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: july 27, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: $15.57&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc/playstation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;very fun in cooperative play, up to 10 players&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;great variety of different gameplay elements&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;combat is clunky&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;progression too grindy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;needs more content&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 7.3/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 20 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">death’s door</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/20/deathsdoor.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="death's door" /><published>2021-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-20T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/20/deathsdoor</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/20/deathsdoor.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/deathsdoor.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;death’s door&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: acid nerve&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: isometric action adventure puzzle rpg&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: july 20, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: $16.39&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, xbox&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;magical art style and sound design&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;memorable, well designed boss fights&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;extremely smooth combat&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;engaging story with lots of lore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rewarding exploration&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;lack of map&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tedious navigation&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 9/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 20 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">batbarian: testament of the primordials (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/14/batbarian.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="batbarian: testament of the primordials (full review)" /><published>2021-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-14T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/14/batbarian</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/14/batbarian.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/batbarian.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;batbarian testament of the primordials&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: unspeakable pixels&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: action adventure puzzle platformer metroidvania&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: july 14, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $19.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, playstation, xbox, switch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: ps5&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;innovative assist system with friendly NPCs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;rewarding exploration via loot &amp;amp; lore&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenging puzzles &amp;amp; platforming&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;diverse set of enemy types &amp;amp; bosses&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;excellent accessibility options&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;unclear signs of how to progress the story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;random difficulty spikes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dialogue choices don’t provide any different outcomes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: full&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 20 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? no&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Batman the Batbarian, a stylish Bat-roidvania&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While there is no shortage of games inspired by Metroid and Castlevania, Batbarian: Testament of the Primordials is a jack of all trades. Not only is it an action-adventure puzzle game; it also successfully encompasses elements from many different genres. This eccentric and humorous, 2D pixel art, side-scrolling Metroidvania really brings out the nostalgia of old NES titles while exuberating modern day humor, aesthetic, and gaming mechanics.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In an over the top fashion, you, the titular barbarian, and your pet bat Pip are immediately thrown off a cliff by a group of ogres, plummeting to the bottom of a mysterious cave. With no light source other than Pip, you must navigate your way out of this cave and figure out what happened in the events that led up to this moment. The story is told in retrospect and pieced together with flashbacks and visions as you progress in the game. Batbarian’s level design pays homage to that of a classic Metroidvania game by throwing you into situations in which you do not know how to proceed. Vines, boulders, walls block the way until you learn a new skill that allows you to advance in this direction in the future. A major component of Metroidvania games and a marker of success for games of said genre is exploration and backtracking. Batbarian incentivizes these two gameplay elements by rewarding you with secret treasure rooms where you can find permanent stat upgrades among other rare commodities. The only complaint about exploration is that there is generally no direction on how to advance, so you may end up aimlessly exploring rooms that lead nowhere.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the game holds your hand in the beginning with tutorials and hints, you will quickly be left with nothing but your brains and wits to figure out what to do next. The first few rooms of the cave serve as the game’s way of teaching you the basics, where you learn to jump, slash, and direct Pip to solve puzzles and defeat enemies. Combat mechanics are simple enough with a single attack that you can spam, and a charge attack that you can unlock later on. The puzzle mechanics are jumps, triggering switches, and directing Pip, or some combination of all three. When you level up, a slot machine mini-game appears, in which you can increase one of three stats (strength, defense, awareness). Though the minor increase of these stats barely contribute to the sense of progression, they do provide a break from the puzzling, platforming, hacking and slashing. While your trusty bat companion will be by your side the entirety of the game, you do not have full control of Pip. Instead, you command her by throwing fruit for her to eat, where different types of fruit allow her to perform a different action. This gameplay mechanic is both innovative and frustrating at times as there are puzzles that require you to command Pip and jump on a platform at the same time. Along your journey, you also meet other characters that agree to assist you and become companions with their own abilities and backstories. You also cannot control them. Instead, each character that you recruit has their own ability, from throwing bombs to shooting magic balls. These abilities are not unlimited either, as they are restricted by a stamina gauge that can only be refilled at a save point or by killing enemies. The combat and puzzles in Batbarian are more about execution than finding the solution, as the game requires you to manage the position of not only yourself and Pip, but also other enemies and obstacles on the screen. Even though the requirement of immaculate timing and execution can be frustrating sometimes, this type of gameplay is satisfying and refreshing as it forces you to think outside the box for an answer.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a puzzle platformer, this game presents a strong narrative, and even introduces branching dialogue choices and multiple endings. A minor disappointment is that most branching dialogue options make no difference to the outcome of the story, but instead provide varietal humor for you to enjoy when playing through the game again. For a game that relies heavily on comedy, Batbarian never over does itself, managing to tell its story in a witty and subtle manner. It has a little something for everyone: a true secret ending for those looking for a fleshed-out narrative, and an in-game speed run timer for those looking to test their skills or look for a challenge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps one of the most commendable feats of this game are its performance and accessibility options. Shamefully, so many release-day titles are riddled with bugs and crashes that any 1.0 launch that plays like a 1.0 launch is a pleasant surprise. Batbarian: Testament of the Primordials runs at a silky smooth 60fps on the PS5 with extremely fast loading times and no bugs. In addition, Batbarian boasts an extremely impressive list of accessibility options that range from slow aim, health regen, more ambient lighting, boosted attack and defense and open the game up to a wider audience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;With an in-your-face title and wacky cover art, Batbarian: Testament of the Primordials was not my cup of tea to begin with, but became more and more impressive with time. There are so many games out there today that attempt to pull off multiple gameplay elements but end up falling short of their lofty ambitions. However, Batbarian: Testament of the Primordials does a wonderful job of weaving together its beautiful artwork, ambient soundtrack, witty story, inventive puzzles, and evolving combat mechanics. Along with its refreshing arsenal of accessibility options and dozens of hours of gameplay, Batbarian is truly a hidden gem that Metroidvania and puzzle lovers will fall in love with right off the bat (no pun intended).&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">out of line (full review)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/01/ool.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="out of line (full review)" /><published>2021-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2021-07-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/01/ool</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2021/07/01/ool.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/ool.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;mos&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;out of line&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: nerd monkeys&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;genre: puzzle platformer&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;multiplayer/co-op: no&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: june 23, 2021&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: a review copy of the title was provided by the publisher for review purposes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;msrp: $12.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;platforms: pc, playstation, xbox, switch&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;reviewed on: pc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;pros:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;luscious hand-painted art-style&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;atmospheric soundtrack &amp;amp; audio effects&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;imaginative puzzle solving with spear-wielding mechanic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;collaboration with friendly NPC’s&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;cons:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;overall short game&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;minor bugs that force you to re-load checkpoint&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ambiguous/confusing narrative&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 7.25/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;buy at full price, sale, never: sale&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 2.5 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of Line is a charming indie puzzle platformer whose world appears almost surreal due to its hand-drawn artwork.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You play as San, an ambiguous being trying to escape from a factory, constantly stalked by corrupted machinery. The narrative is presented without dialogue, making it obscure, and the overall story is pieced together via context clues and murals seen in the game’s luscious backdrops. Unfortunately, the story is told solely using artwork, which makes it feel incomplete. After the game, I had a gist of the overarching narrative, but ended up with more questions than answers.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Along your way, you encounter other amorphous characters that come to your aid. Out of Line does a fantastic job of synchronizing San’s actions with these characters in order to progress by activating a platform or avoiding the treacherous machinery. For a single player game, Out of Line unexpectedly juxtaposes the loneliness felt in a world desolated by robot claws and distorted gadgetry with its “cooperative play”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Out of Line differentiates itself from traditional puzzle platformers with the newly introduced spear mechanic. Instead of being used as a weapon, the spear can be hurled and utilized as a platform on walls and a key to power up devices. A minor disappointment is that there is no combat in this game, despite the fact that you wield this powerful tool. It cannot be thrown as a weapon and does no damage to enemies if you attempt to do so.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Though the puzzles are quite easy, the game does a great job ramping up the player to increasingly challenging problems. The puzzles start off simple enough, asking you to create a single platform with the spear, and go as far as requiring you to correctly time spear throws and jumps. There are, of course, additional puzzle elements that include stopping gadgets from rotating with your spear, guiding friendly beetle-like creatures into powering machinery and redirecting pipes to let out steam. In addition, the puzzles are not repeated for the sake of artificially prolonging the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For a 2-3 hour game, Out of Line is a fun straightforward puzzle platformer filled with relaxing scenery, innovative puzzles, gorgeous art design, and a vague but intriguing story. Other than to gather all collectibles for the trophy achievement, there is little to no replayability for this game. Priced at $12.99, this game is better purchased during a sale, especially for those that are on the fence. Though Out of Line does not break the mold of puzzle platformer games, it is a game worth checking out if you have a desire for a visual and sensory experience and a free evening.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry></feed>