<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.8.6">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2020-06-21T19:04:48-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">henry y.</title><subtitle></subtitle><entry><title type="html">resident evil 7: biohazard gold edition</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/06/15/re7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="resident evil 7: biohazard gold edition" /><published>2020-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/06/15/re7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/06/15/re7.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/re7.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;re7&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;resident evil 7: biohazard gold edition&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;includes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dlc: banned footage volume 1&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dlc: banned footage volume 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dlc: end of zoe&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;dlc: not a hero&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: capcom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: january 23rd, 2017&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: $16.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: /10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: /10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: /10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: n/a hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? n/a&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;coming soon&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">remnant: from the ashes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/06/01/rfta.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="remnant: from the ashes" /><published>2020-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-06-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/06/01/rfta</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/06/01/rfta.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/remnant.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;remnant&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;remnant: from the ashes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: gunfire games&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: august 19th, 2019&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: $23.99&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 8.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 6/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 8.5/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 7.7/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 43 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes (not including dlc)&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;coming soon&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">final fantasy vii remake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/05/15/ff7.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="final fantasy vii remake" /><published>2020-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-15T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/05/15/ff7</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/05/15/ff7.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/cloud.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;cloud&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;final fantasy vii remake&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: square enix&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: april 10th, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: $45.77 (pre-order)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 10/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8.5/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 75 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;music:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;ahead on our way&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;jessie’s theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;tifa’s theme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;midnight rendezvous&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;star of seventh heaven&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;smash ‘em rip ‘em&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;main theme of final fantasy vii&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;flowers blooming in the church&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To preface this review, I never played the original game (Final Fantasy VII) released in 1997 for the Playstation. As such, I played this game for what it is as a standalone, not in comparison to what it was back in 1997. However, for a game revolving so much around character development and storytelling, I felt compelled to play through the original game, so a review/comparison of that will be coming soon! This review will (hopefully) be based solely on the remake though.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy is a Japanese role playing game series known for its world building, characterisation, music, and storytelling. Each Final Fantasy has its own universe and story, and tends to focus on a group of characters from seemingly different backgrounds who come together to save their world from destruction or domination by a central antagonist. Final Fantasy VII is no different, as the story has many depths to uncover, secrets to tell, twists to discover, and characters to grow attached to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You play as Cloud Strife, an arrogant, proud, and mostly quiet mercenary at first. He is uninterested in anything beyond his job and getting paid.  He later discovers more about his past and, with the help of his friends and through his hardships, learns there is more to being a hero than possessing physical strength and fame, developing compassion for the planet and people he fights to protect. Cloud joins an eco-terrorist organization called AVALANCHE to stop a megacorporation known as Shinra Electric Company from using the planet’s life essence as an energy source. The events of Final Fantasy VII Remake only take place in Midgar, which makes up about 10% of the original game’s events.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Although there are plenty of side quests and missions to do to keep the playthrough exciting, this game is not “open world” and runs fairly linear. Usually, “open world” is a mechanic utilized in games so that the player can freely explore and approach objectives as opposed to a structured storyline. Open world games, when done well, foster emergent gameplay as no two players will experience the world in the same fashion. In Final Fantasy VII Remake, certain dialogue choices and decisions can affect minor events but the overall structure of the story is straightforward. There are quite a number of unique mini-games that can get quite hard if you are looking for a break from the direct story. More importantly, despite not being an open world, the world of Final Fantasy VII feels… full. The citizens of Midgar populate the streets you walk by, having their conversations that you can listen in on and sometimes interact with. Though a small detail in the big picture, it makes the atmosphere of the game that much better, making you feel like you’re living in Midgar yourself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Final Fantasy VII is a visually stunning game and the graphics quality and animations done for this game are nothing short of amazing. There are seamless transitions between cutscenes and gameplay that make you feel as if you are watching a movie. One very minor nitpick is that there are a lot of cutscenes, so much that it may feel very slow for you.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There are 4 game modes offered: Classic, Easy, Normal and Hard. Classic Mode is the equivalent of setting the difficulty to Easy, with the exception that all of your characters move around, block, and attack automatically as they are controlled by the AI. The only thing for the player to do is cast spells or use items. This is the developer’s effort to make the game as “turn-based” as possible, which pays homage to the original turn-based Final Fantasy VII game. It doesn’t do a great job though… While Easy and Normal modes are fairly self-explanatory, Hard mode is only unlocked after you beat the game on any other mode. The difficulty spike that comes with Hard mode is: enemies are stronger; you cannot use items; and MP (used to cast spells) is not restored at benches. Benches are locations that your characters can rest at to restore HP and MP. The extra incentive for players to complete the game on Hard mode are the secret boss fights only available in that difficulty. Hard mode is fair, challenging, fun, and overall an improvement from Easy and Normal, as it makes gameplay more tactical and calculated and punishes you for button mashing.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Originally, all Final Fantasy games utilized “turn-based” mechanics in terms of gameplay. However, Final Fantasy VII Remake’s combat system utilizes a quasi turn-based and real-time system. Regular attacks are performed in real time. However, when casting a spell, executing an ability, or using an item, you are able to “pause” the game to select which action you want each character to perform. This new hybrid combat system is inspired by the well-known and widely-used battle system called Active Time Battle (ATB) which in itself is already a pseudo-turn-based combat system. Originally introduced in Final Fantasy IV,  ATB allows characters to perform an action when the gauge is full. The fill rate is affected by stats, status effects, abilities used and other factors requiring the player to be economical with time, thus making it a pseudo-turn-based system.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Perhaps what made me fall in love with this game was its beautiful soundtrack. Each piece just makes you feel so reminiscent, nostalgic and emotional. There’s even a side quest that sends you to find music discs to be played in a jukebox! The music of Final Fantasy VII Remake consists of orchestral as well as synth pieces and is what may very well define the game along with its story. The remake pays homage to the soundtrack of the original game with new remixes as well as introduces a new score by Nobuo Uematsu, Masashi Hamauzu and Mitsuto Suzuki. In addition to the music, the voice acting quality is also amazing. Each voice really matches the personality and image of each character. The voice really makes the characters, the characters! Although the voice acting cast for the remake is entirely different from the cast from before, I have faith for the next generation of voice actors for Final Fantasy VII.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My first playthrough of Final Fantasy VII clocked in at around 35 hours, doing all the side quests I could. I platinumed the game at 75 hours, beating the game on Hard mode, defeating the secret boss, and collecting all collectibles. After beating the game for the first time, you will unlock Chapter Select and Hard Mode. Chapter Select allows you to replay a particular chapter instead of having to restart the game over again in case you missed anything in your first playthrough.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I very much enjoyed and cherished playing Final Fantasy VII Remake. Since Final Fantasy VII Remake only makes up about 10% of the original, I am curious what the future parts to the remake will have in store. In addition, the ending of the story in this game ends up being divergent from the original game, so it is unknown whether the future remakes will align with that of the original. Although I said I would write this review solely based on this game alone, and not the original, I cannot help but do so because the game relies very heavily on its narrative and storytelling. Without revealing any spoilers, this game introduced an entity known as “The Whispers”, which are basically arbiters of fate that enforce the course of destiny or basically keep the timeline of the remake to be the same as the original. Certain events that occur in the remake cause a disruption in the timeline that may very much not align with that of the original Final Fantasy VII. Given the title Final Fantasy VII Remake, players hold the expectation that the events in the original are held to the same fate as in the remake. If the developers wanted to make a re-rendition of Final Fantasy VII, perhaps they should have named it differently. Nonetheless, I am looking forward to the next installment in the now confirmed trilogy of remakes of Final Fantasy VII.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">resident evil 3 remake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/05/01/re3.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="resident evil 3 remake" /><published>2020-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-05-01T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/05/01/re3</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/05/01/re3.html">&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/jill.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;jill&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;resident evil 3 remake + resident evil resistance&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;developer: capcom&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;release date: april 3rd, 2020&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;price: $46.79 (pre-order)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge: 9/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value: 7/10&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade: 8/10&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;total score: 8/10&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;hours spent on the game: 40 hours&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;platinumed? yes&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To preface this review: I never played the original game (Resident Evil 3: Nemesis) released in 1999 for the Playstation. As such, I played this game for what it is as a standalone, not in comparison to what it was back in 1999 nor to the Resident Evil 2 Remake from 2019.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Resident Evil franchise is known to have coined the genre “survival horror”, which is known for its maze-like maps, puzzles, inventory management, and ominous ambience. Players are crippled through limited ammunition, health, or speed to add to the players lack of control. However, the game does introduce some new gameplay elements, perhaps inspired from games of the Dark Souls genre, such as performing perfect dodges that reward players with a window to counter attack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The narrative of the game ties in with those of the rest of the games in the franchise and fits the classic zombie movie trope. Raccoon City is infected by the outbreak of the T-virus, which turns everyone into zombies. You switch between playing as one of the two main protagonists of the game – Jill Valentine, who is part of the Special Tactics And Rescue Service (STARS) and Carlos Oliveira, who is part of the Umbrella Biohazard Countermeasure Service (UBCS) – as they try to survive and find the vaccine for the virus. You aim to defeat the pharmaceutical conglomerate Umbrella, who is responsible for creating and releasing the virus. At the beginning of the game, you are immediately thrown into action as you are pursued by the biological weapon of which this game is known for: Nemesis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Character development is also very well executed. Jill is put in imminent danger and beaten down so many times, a sign that despite being the main character, she is still human. Carlos flirts with Jill quite a handful of times and shows that he actually cares for her. Carlos’ comments on how weird the doors are in the subway station and mentioning how our tax dollars are used to pay for art further pushes the idea that our main protagonists are human just like us.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The thing that I immediately noticed was how visually stunning the graphics were. The game provides no shortage of scenes that make you feel like you are watching a movie rather than playing a game. One thing I really respect and appreciate is Capcom’s attention to detail. You can zoom in on a wall and observe its textures or focus in on a book and read the text legibly. I noticed that they put more care into every character’s expressions. There are also many scripts and books scattered throughout the game that you can read to gain further information on the lore.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;To cater to players of all demographics, new players and veterans alike, the game offers five modes: Assisted, Standard, Hardcore, Nightmare, and Inferno. On Assisted mode, you get an extra assault rifle with auto aim and health regeneration. You will only unlock Nightmare mode after you beat Hardcore mode and Inferno mode after you beat Nightmare mode. In Inferno mode, everything is altered. All the enemy and item location from previous modes will be changed, so you cannot depend on clearing it off memorization of past playthroughs. There are less save points, no auto checkpoints, less ammo/healing items, and you will die after 1-2 hits from enemies. This emphasizes the need to learn how to perfect dodge. These five different modes greatly increase replayability. Resident Evil games were never “long” games to begin with, as players are encouraged to speed run through playthroughs, learning which items are essential and which routes are optimal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This game is hard, but fair, and I appreciate that. There will be times in the game where you forgot to pick up an item, exhausted too many bullets, or were low on healing items. There will always be enough ammunition and healing items scattered throughout a boss arena to progress you through the game. It is Capcom’s attention to these gameplay details that have drawn me to play more of them!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Albeit a “short” game with a single playthrough of around 5 hours, this game gave me around 40 total hours worth of play, including the time it took to complete the hardest difficulty with S rank and to achieve a Platinum trophy for the game. After your initial playthrough, you will unlock an item shop in which you can complete challenges to unlock points for purchasing additional in-game items, such as an Infinite Ammo Rocket Launcher. With the introduction of these gameplay elements, this promotes more replayability and flexibility to different play styles and strategies.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now for a few gripes that I do have with the game. Although the Resident Evil series is meant to be replayed as well as speed run, the replayability aspect does get dry very fast. With each subsequent playthrough, the game definitely gets less and less exciting and fun as you mostly know what to expect and do. Unless you are a hardcore gamer trying to achieve a record-speed run time, you would probably cease to play through this game after two or three runs. The boss fights in this game are also somewhat underwhelming, with very scripted and expected appearances, which takes away from the survival horror aspect of the game. The price for this game on release, $60 msrp, is also a very steep price for the amount of content you get, even though you do get the online multiplayer game: Resident Evil Resistance included as well. At the end of the day, I still had a lot of fun playing this game and am looking forward to the next game in the series :D!&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">personal take on reviews</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/04/07/personaltakeonreviews.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="personal take on reviews" /><published>2020-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-07T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/04/07/personaltakeonreviews</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/reviews/self/2020/04/07/personaltakeonreviews.html">&lt;p&gt;if you know me, you probably know that i play a lot of video games (and board games). i have come to an unfortunate realization that many reviews from critics or social media gurus are rarely a good representation of a game’s true potential and caliber. these reviews include but are not limited to that of well known companies such as ign, game informer, polygon, gamespot, kotaku and metacritic. these days, an increasing amount of clickbaity titles and pandering editorials fill the pages of these websites. these so-called reviews have become nothing more than paid for fluff from game publishers rather than an honest, down to earth opinion of a game’s quality. in addition, these “reviewers” seldom play a game from start to finish, discover all its nooks and crannies before writing a review. how can you produce a valid opinion if you haven’t even finished the game? often a times, i watch or read a review of a game that has been very negatively reviewed until i play it myself to find it to be quite the opposite. countless video games are unfairly and unjustly criticized, which is what gave me the motivation to start writing my own reviews. however, of course, the nature of a review is subjective. i will try my best to give a holistic, honest review of any game that i play. every game deserves to be given a fair chance to be played, good or bad!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;so what goes inside a review? what are the components of a game that need to be analyzed? for me, i would break it down to the following categories:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;visual
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;does the game look visually appealing? how are the graphics compared to other titles produced in the same year? is the game artistic?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;audio
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how is the soundtrack? is the audio/music fitting with the theme? do you listen to the ost even when not playing?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;gameplay
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;is gameplay smooth and intuitive? is it innovative or basic? (ie. button mashing)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;narrative
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how is the story, character development, and plot? does the game tell the story well, or does it incorporate cheap, cliche tropes/situations&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;challenge
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;is the game challenging/difficult (in a good way?), do you feel accomplished after beating the game? are there difficult decisions to make in the game that ultimately alter your experience? how is the level design?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;replayability
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;how replayable is the game? is there ng+, secret endings, secret difficulties, end game content, multiplayer, side quests?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;value
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;does this game hold its value well? is it worth the amount that you paid for it? how many hours of gameplay?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;personal grade
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;did you personally enjoy the game?&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;for possible preexisting bias, the types of games i personally enjoy playing are action rpg’s that are “exceptionally challenging” (ie. soulsborne games :p)&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;i would give each category a rating from 0-10 then aggregate all of them and give a final score.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;bonus thing to think about
    &lt;ul&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;are games that are entirely or mostly played online considered “good” or “bad” because it is well developed or because your friends/peers all play it? these types of games are definitely more influenced by current societal/cultural trends.&lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;should all categories be weighted the same? for example, a game can have stunning visuals and narrative but very poor gameplay and replayability, would it still be an overall positively rated game?&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ul&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">if you know me, you probably know that i play a lot of video games (and board games). i have come to an unfortunate realization that many reviews from critics or social media gurus are rarely a good representation of a game’s true potential and caliber. these reviews include but are not limited to that of well known companies such as ign, game informer, polygon, gamespot, kotaku and metacritic. these days, an increasing amount of clickbaity titles and pandering editorials fill the pages of these websites. these so-called reviews have become nothing more than paid for fluff from game publishers rather than an honest, down to earth opinion of a game’s quality. in addition, these “reviewers” seldom play a game from start to finish, discover all its nooks and crannies before writing a review. how can you produce a valid opinion if you haven’t even finished the game? often a times, i watch or read a review of a game that has been very negatively reviewed until i play it myself to find it to be quite the opposite. countless video games are unfairly and unjustly criticized, which is what gave me the motivation to start writing my own reviews. however, of course, the nature of a review is subjective. i will try my best to give a holistic, honest review of any game that i play. every game deserves to be given a fair chance to be played, good or bad!</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">why here</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/blog/self/2020/04/06/introduction.html" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="why here" /><published>2020-04-06T00:00:00-07:00</published><updated>2020-04-06T00:00:00-07:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/blog/self/2020/04/06/introduction</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/blog/self/2020/04/06/introduction.html">&lt;p&gt;filler for now.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">filler for now.</summary></entry></feed>